Guide to the W. Y. (Walter Yeeling) Evans-Wentz Papers, 1894-1961
Department of Special Collections
W. Y. (Walter Yeeling) Evans-Wentz Papers,
1894-1961
Special Collections M0278
Evans-Wentz, W. Y. (Walter Yeeling), 1878-1965.
5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of the Estate of Walter Y. Evans-Wentz, 1978.
Biographical Note
Walter Yeeling Evans-Wentz helped to develop western understanding of Oriental religions, especially Tibetan Buddhism. He was born February 2, 1878 in Trenton, New Jersey where he spent his childhood, completing elementary school in June, 1892. After less than two years of high school, Wantz decided to become a journalist. He dropped out of high school and enrolled in commercial courses at business colleges in Jacksonville, Florida and Trenton, New Jersey. Working his way across the United States in various newspaper offices, he followed his family, who had recently settled in La Mesa, California, westward. Having decided that he was not well-suited to journalism, he arrived in Palo Alto in the academic year 1901-1902, hoping to gain admittance to the newly-established Stanford University.
Since Wentz had not completed high school, he was forced to make up deficiencies through special studies under various tutors. In May 1902 he passed an exam in English composition at Stanford, thus enabling him to submit an application for admittance to the University as a special student. Despite this initial handicap, Wentz graduated with his class in autumn 1906 (the graduation ceremonies having been postponed due to the severe earthquake that had demolished many of Stanford's buildings in April); he was elected Phi Beta Kappa. While at Stanford, Wentz wrote many poems, several extolling California in general and Stanford in particular, that were published, as were a couple of essays, in the Sequoia, a student literary publication. As a Stanford undergraduate, Wentz strongly believed that mankind had a great potentiality for spiritual and moral goodness if educated men would actively work to alleviate the social ills. He was impressed with Mrs. Leland Stanford's dream that the University's Memorial Church would encourage the students' highest spiritual ideals without being involved in denominational squabbles. Having been raised a Uniterian in the tradition of Ralph Waldo Emerson, Wentz fit nicely into the religious ideals fostered at Stanford. In his senior year he helped found the Social Service Club, whose advisor was Chaplain Gardiner and whose first president was Wentz. Only a month after its founding, the members of the Social Service Club had their first opportunity for social action by helping the victims of the earthquake find food and shelter.
Wentz majored in English at Stanford and became interested in Celtic influences on English literature. His advisor, Professor Newcomer, encouraged Wentz to pursue this interest by working for a Master's degree during the academic year 1906-1907. Another professor had a great influence on Wentz's development: William James was a visiting professor at Stanford in the spring semester 1906, teaching an introductory course in Philosophy. From James, Wentz developed an interest in the study of religious experience and the philosophical idea of a panpsychic reality that permeates all of human existence. What was always a philosophical possibility for James became a religious probability for Wentz. After receiving his M.A. in June 1907, Wentz went to Europe. He earned the Docteur-es-Lettres in 1909 at the University of Rennes for literary work in the field of Celtic folk-lore. At this time Wentz affirmed his own part-Celtic ancestry by adding Evans to his name. A year later he earned the Bachelor of Science in Anthropology from Oxford University for work on the Celtic fairy-faith. Evans-Wentz's literary work on Celtic folklore, which was begun at Stanford and concluded in France, was combined with his anthropological study of Celtic religion and overlaid with a panpsychical theory to explain the data in his first book, The Fairy-Faith in Celtic Countries (London: Oxford University Press, 1911).
Between 1911 and 1917, Evans-Wentz traveled extensively through the Mediterranian countries, documenting the religious experiences of many peoples. He spent three years in Egypt, not only studying Islamic faith, but also examining some of the Coptic documents of the early Christian gnostic communities and some of the ancient Egyptian texts from Karnak.
His five-year sojourn in India, Sikkim, and Ceylon between 1917 and 1922 provided the material for his most important works. These years for the most part were not spent in the theoretical study of Tibetan Buddhism, but rather in living the religion he was studying, attempting to experience the life of the people on their own terms. He climbed mountains with pilgrims who were imploring the deities to cure them of their maladies, visited various ashrams, and became a Buddhist novice monk in Sikkim between 1920 and 1922. Despite his close proximity to the religious rituals of the Indian people, he always remained the carefully-trained anthropologist who evaluated his data in a scholarly manner, attempting to illuminate the Buddhist religious experience in lights of Western religious phenomena. In recognition of his contribution be scholarship the honorary degree of Doctor of Science in Comparative Religion was conferred by Oxford University in 1931. Thus, when Evans-Wentz first met Lama Kazi Dawa-Samdup in Sikkim [UNK], he recognized the Lama as a Buddhist scholar whose piety and [UNK] were beyond question. Their brief relationship ([UNK] [UNK] died in 1922) proved to be mutually rewarding. At the time of their first encounter, the Lama was involved in translating several important Tibetan Buddhist texts into English. Evans-Wentz [UNK] his living dictionary and eventually edited these manuscripts so that they would be intelligible to the Western reader. These translations provided the material for Evans-Wentz's four most important books, Tibet's Great Yogi, Milarepa; The Tibetan Book of the Dead; Tibetan Yoga and Secret Doctrines; and The Tibetan Book of the Great Liberation (first published in London by Oxford University Press in 1928, 1929, 1935, and 1954, respectively). Together these four books have gone through at least fifteen printings or editions and there are translations of some of these works in at least five foreign languages. The years between 1922 and Evans-Wentz's death (at 87) on July 17, 1965 were spent editing these four books and writing a fifth book, The Sacred Mountains of the Western World (unpublished). His consuming vocation was to improve understanding between the East and the West. He traveled frequently between Oxford University, the United States, and India. In order to continue his work he laft a large portion of his estate to Stanford University. The fund provides an annual lectureship in his name on topics in the field of Oriental religion, philosophy, and ethics.
Thomas V. Peterson and William A. Clebsch
August 1970
Scope and Content
Correspondence, books, notes, printed material, ephemera, and photographs pertaining to Mahayana Buddhism. Also contains materials pertaining to Evans-Wentz's education.
Container List
- Correspondence A-B (Box 1, Folder 1)
  (inc. G. Warrington [UNK])
- Correspondence C (Box 1, Folder 2)
  (includes Chang, Chen-Chi 10/1955 to 7/1957 7 TLS [UNK] enc. [UNK] 1 ALS [UNK] Vow of Mahamudra by Dorge Tcc from E-W to Bollingen Foundation concerning Chang
  ALS from D. T. Suzuki to Chang concerning E-W)
  [UNK]
- Correspondence D (Box 1, Folder 3)
  (includes Dhammashnna, Nun ANS [UNK] Tcc The Guru Ngrjuna)
- Correspondence E-F-G (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence Lama Govinda March 1955 to June 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  ALS (1) TLS (8) ACS (1) Tcc Thanka of the Eight Forms of Guru Padmasambhava
- Correspondence H-J (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence J-K (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence L-M (Box 1, Folder 8)
  (includes letter from T.E. Lawrence 10/12/1916 ALS)
- Correspondence Mc-N (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence O-P (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence Q-R (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence S (Box 1, Folder 12)
  (includes Spiegelberg, Frederick 2/1952 to 10/1961 TLS (3) [UNK] TMs Tibetan Block Prints)
- Correspondence E. T. Sturdy June 1931 - May 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  (includes ALS from Ambrose Sturdy (son) [UNK] ALS from R.J.R. Scott (son-in-law) to Mrs. Stokes)
- Correspondence T-U-V (Box 2, Folder 1)
  (includes Verrill, Ruth 3/1959 to 5/1959 ALS (2) Msp of symbols cc A Proposal for Designation by William Coxon
- Correspondence Henry Tate February 1960 to July 1960, TLS (10) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence VIP's June 1954 to April 1957, TLS (7) TL (2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence W-Z, ALS (2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  (includes Waters, Frank 4/1957 to 7/1963 TLS (2) & Wentz, Lillian (sister-in-law) 2/1901 to 3/1901
- Correspondence Unidentified (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence By E-W October 1927 to March 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence W/father June 1899 to June 1900 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence Legal miscellany February 1878 to September 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence Concerning E-W March 1938 to February 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  (inc. Frank Waters to G.W. Boss)
- Misc. writings by E-W (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - A Voyage from SAn Diego to San Francisco Ams May 12, 1902
  - The Science of Environment reprint from The Theosophical Forum May 1942
  - Right Views Versus Wrong Views: A Confutative Critique of The Tibetan Book of the Dead printed by the Griffin & Richmond Printing Co., Ltd, Ontario, Canada
  - Remarks made by E-W at the conclusion of Dr. John Gayner Banks' lecture on Contemporary Religion September 25, 1944Tms
  - Confidence and Peace and Security reprint from The Theosophica Forum, Nov. 1945, (3)
  - Tibet's Great Yogi Milarepa reprinted from The Maha Bodhi April - May 1950, (2)
  - Confidence, Peace and Security World Buddhism September 1943
  - Foreward to Immortal Man by John N. East July 1960Ams
  - Foreward (The Light from the East) to The American Philosopher Tms
  - Foreward to a volume of American-born messages from Meher Baba of India Tms (1) Tcc (1) Ams (1)
- Misc. articles by others (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Appeal, unidentified author T
  - Ibbotson, Ruth, The Art of Meditation Tms
  - Extracts from The Theosophical Society - address delivered by Col. H. S. Olcott, President Theosophical Society Tcc
- Diaries: 1894, 1895, 1896, Jan 1897 - May 1899 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Diaries: May 26, 1899 - June 30, 1899, June 30, 1899 - Aug 9, 1899, Aug 10, 1899 - June 1, 1900, June 1, 1900 - July 15, 1900, July 19, 1900 - Aug 23, 1900, Aug 1900 - Sept 1901, Sept 1901 - Feb 1902, Jan 1902 - Oct 2, 1903. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bank book 1939-1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Address books, (2)
- Notes on Ultra-violet rays, (1P)
- Books referring to my books for library, (1p list)
- Notes on readings
- Notes on Mrs. McCollum's health lectures, San Diego, 1943
- Bibliography and notes of readings in San Diego: Notes on Dr. Hononseck's lectures on health
- On Mexico (Scholastic note book)
- Book I: notes on readings, (blue notepad)
- Notes on readings, (Memorandum - brown notepad)
- Notes on lectures by T.R. Gaines 1961
- Notes on Mrs. Holmes lectures 1942
- Essays & papers (academic) 1902-1903 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Essays & papers (academic) 1904 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Essays & papers (academic) 1905 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Education (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Certificate for promotion from seventh grade, Trenton, NJ 1892
  - Recommendation for High School Teacher's Certificate, Stanford, 190[UNK]
  - Duplicate recommendaton for High School Teacher's Certificate
  - Stanford University Fifteenth Annual Commencement program, 1906
  - Phi Beta Kappa - Beta of California Chapter in Stanford booklet
  - Envelope from Harvard University addressed to E-W
  - To whom it may concern letter from David Starr Jordan, Stanford Sept. 1922, (copy)
  - To whom it may concern letter from O.L. Elliott, Stanford 1922, ([UNK])
  - To whom it may concern letter from J. E. McDowell, Stanford Sept. 1922, (copy)
  - Certificate of Composition for University Dues from University of Oxford, February 1931
  - University Registry letter, Oxford March 1930
  - Maha Bodhi Society of India Diploma February 1956
  - Ballot for election of officers, class of 1906 dated Sept 1905
  - Calling card of E-W of Jesus College, Oxford and Stanford Univ
  - Phi Beta Kappa Notice April 1906
  - Envelope from county superintendent of schools, Los Angeles to E-W
  - Envelope marked 1906 commencement
  - Certificate from University of Oxford for Bachelor of Science June 1910plus envelope
  - Certificate of Phi Beta Kappa membership, Fairclough and Elliott o Stanford, April 12, 1906
  - Diploma from The Universal Brotherhood and Theosophical Society January 6, 1903
- Fragment of Oxford Graduation gown (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Articles on Eastern & other Religions by E-W & others (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Preface to The Tibetan Book of the Dead, (specimen pages)
  - Review of Tibet's Great Yog Milarepa by H. Lee Shuttleworth
  - Review in Reviews and Notices of Tibet's Great Yog Milarepa
  - Dharmapala, Angarika The, The Buddhist Empire of Asoka the Great 1909
  - Evans-Wentz, W.Y., La Idea de La Reencarnacion
  - Sheet listing three books on Tibetan Religion and Yoga Practices by E-W
  - Edge, H.T. Reincarnation and Christianity article
  - H.P., Simplicity of the Fundamental article
  - Theosophical items of Interest to both sides
  - Hansen, Louis A., Why I am a Vegetarian, pamphlet
  - Essene School of Life List of Publications
  - Smith, Joseph, The Prophet Joseph Smith Tells His Own Story
  - English 8 - requirements in English 8 class
  - Schmiedeler, Edgar, Birth Control A Catholic View in Reader's Digest 1943
  - Abbreviations used in marking themes
  - Reincarnation, The Theosophical Society, publisher
  - Introduction to Tibet's Great Yog Milarepa by W. Y. Evans-Wentz
  - Program for Unitarian Church, Bard Hall, San Diego, CA
  - Bogey - publication at Stanford Univ
  - Who are the Mahatmans?, The Theosophical Society, publishers
  - Van Norman, Louis E., Our Need for an Inner Sanctuary - condensation of a lecture
  - The Three Wars, presented by Chas. V. Gridley Camp, No. 104
  - Sinica, May 1929, pp 63, 64, 71 72, 91, 92, 93, 94 and 2 illus.
  - Suddhammachari, Sister, Jaya Mangala Gth, pamphlet
  - Holdridge, Herbert C., A Message to the North American Indians
  - Lawrence, D. H., De-Bunking the Mexican Indian
  - Gaskill, Gordon, Ceylon: Isle of Delight
  - Verrill, Ruth Mrs. - notebook with thirty one pages of notes
  - Hoskin, Clarence, Tricks of Indian Monkeys on Jungle Roads
  - Cohen, J. M., The Craft of Dying - Cohen on The Tibetan Book of the Dead
  - Stover, Allan J. The Rhythm of Life March 1945, 2pp
  - Office notes from The Canadian Theosophist Jan 1945, 2pp
  - Keeler, Clyde, The Worship of Ishtar Among the Cuna Indians of San Blas 1955pamphlet
- Calling cards & misc. items (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Box of visiting cards
  - Note of address of Mrs Victel
  - Various calling cards, (10)
  - Picture of Manila Cathedral
  - Drawing of two Oriental warriors on handmade paper
  - Oriental characters on handmade paper
  - Map with photographs surrounding the map
  - Program of the play Johnson Over Jordan by J. B. Priestley-Saville Theatre
  - Bookcover of The Tibetan Book of the Dead by E-W
  - Bookcover of Masked Gods by Frank Waters
- Notebooks (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Tibetan rough translation of The Tibetan Book of the Great Liberation
  - Biography of Lobzang M. Darji
  - Quotations
  - Tibetan Book of Liberation, Notebook I
  - Tibetan Book of Liberation, Notebook II
  - Tibetan Book of Liberation 2nd Revision (complete text)
  - I Chelaship: its Nature & its Tests; the Pledge; the Paramitas; the Exalted Eightfold Path; Esoteric Discipline
  - II The Esoteric or Oriental School
  - Notes & Abstracts & Poems
  - American Indian Lore
  - Guru Pema's Life, I, II, III, IV, V, VI Notebooks
  - Translation of The Brief Precepts composed by Ugen Peme, (1)
  - Art of Prayer to the Bodhisattvas, (2)
  - The Tibetan Book of the Great Liberation translated text
  - Notes (1) from Sarat Chandra Das, Tibetan-English Dictionary Calcutta, 1902
  - Notes (3) from Sarat Chandra Das, Tibetan-English Dictionary
  - Glossary
  - Extracts & notes from The Urga Manuscript in translation
- Notes and booklets on nutrition (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - McCollum Laboratories Food Guide
  - McCollum 21-Day Miracle Menu
  - Brochure for A New Way of Life by Thomas Gaines
  - Notes to Lectures by Thomas Gaines, June 10, 1948Mss [UNK], 14pp; 1p of added notes
  - Notes on Curing Certain Tropical Diseases Mss, 4pp
  - Description of Lord of Heal ing Tibetan Painting by Almora, U.P., India March 11, 1940Mss
  - Extracts from the Sutra of the Lord of Healing Mss by Almora U.P. possibly, 4pp
  - Gaines, Thomas, Secrets of Cosmic Power 1947, 1p
  - Certificate of E-W for completion of course in Health Science by Paul C. Bragg 2/18/43 in envelope
  - Bragg, Paul Health-Vitality Youthfulness and Long Life through Nutritional Awakening, Ten pamphlets 2/2/43, 2/3/43, 2/4/43, 2/5/43, 2/7/43, 2/8/43, 2/9/43, 2/10/43, 2/11,43, 2/12/43
  - Advertisement for Life-Transforming course of Health by Thomas Gaines, 1p
  - Gaines, Thomas Scientific Breathing Principles June 10, 1948lecture, 1p
  - Gaines, Thomas, The Art of Sight Improvement June 11, 1948, 1p
  - Gaines, Thomas, 20 Important Food Facts June 12, 1948, 2pp
  - Gaines, Thomas, Special List of Corrective Meals, 1p
  - Gaines, Thomas, Rejuvenation, Youth & Beauty June 14, 1948, 1p
  - Gaines, Thomas Poise, Relaxation, Inner Peace, Brain Rejuvenation: June 14, 1948, 1p
  - Gaines, Thomas Success is for You June 15, 1948, 1p
  - Gaines, Thomas Health and Healing of Body and Mind June 15, 1948, 1p
  - Devi, Indra Class Notes on Yoga softcover book with photograph of Devi, 20pp
  - The Life and Resurrection of Jesus the Christ Coptic Fellowship of America, 11pp
  - The Chemistry of Food and its Application for Health Coptic Fellowship of America, 9pp
  - Proper Nutrition and Food Value Coptic Fellowship of America, 8pp
  - Health and Beauty Coptic Fellowship of America, 7pp
  - Bragg, Paul C. Colitis & Ulcers 1940, 14pp
  - Gaines, Thomas, The Miracle Month 1944, 64pp
- The Fairy Faith (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Preface to the First American Edition by E-W Tms (1) cc (3)
  - Foreward by Geoffrey Hodson Tms 2pp, cc 5pp (1) cc 200 (2)
    with ms corrections
- The Tibetan Book of the Great Liberation Tcc with ms corrections with cover (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cuchama and Sacred Mountains Tcc with cover (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Photographs which are the illustrations in Cuchama and Sacred Mountains with descriptions of illustrations (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Loose typed pages with ms notes of Cuchama and Sacred Mountains (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Cuchama and Sacred Mountains Tcc without cover (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Incomplete Tms of Coochama & Sacred Mountains with cover (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Extra cc pp of Coochama & Sacred Mountains I (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Extra cc pp of Coochama & Sacred Mountains II
- Ainyahita in Pearls by Otoman-Zar-Adusht-Hanish, 1p original and cc and cover (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Misc. handwritten notes by E-W I (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Misc. handwritten notes by E-W II
- Maps & building plans (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Map of tracts of isolated U.S. land applied for by E-W and newspaper Notice for Publication-Isolated Tract Public Land Sale
  - Map and description of land at Barrett Junction for sale by E-W
  - Plan for week-end house
  - Plan for the yoga Vidyalaya, at Birbhadra, Rishi Kesh, U.P. India (with neg), (1)
  - Plan for pergola and surrounding grounds, (4)
  - Plan for house June 24, 1929, (2)
  - Large handmade map of land
  - Description of size of unidentified lot and house and cost
  - Description of boundary of plot leased to E-W: area 35.26
  - Mineral maps in area around Mt. Tecate, (2); (oversize file)
- Newspaper clippings & Newspapers (Box 8, Folder 2 part I)
  - San Francisco Chronicle, June 3, 1934, 6pp
  - The Morning Post (London) July 28, 1922, 12pp
  - The Buddhist World (Colombo) April 30, 1952, 16pp
  - The Buddhist World (Colombo) April 30, 1952see p21 for article by E-W Let There Be Understanding, 8pp
  - The Buddhist World (Colombo) August 20, 1952, 10pp
  - The Buddhist World (Colombo) December 14, 1953p7 Seek that Wisdom by E-W, (11)
  - The Buddhist World (Colombo) September 2, 1953 The Vatican Condemns What Ceylon Advocates by E-W, (19)
  - The Buddhist World (Colombo) July 23, 1952, 4pp
  - Misc. newsclippings 1904 59 1965
  - Misc. clippings concerning E-W and his family (brother and father) including a letterto the editor on Peace and War by E-W articles Let There be Further Understanding, Seek That Wisdom, The Vatican Condemns What Ceylon Advocates
  - New York Herald September 11, 1904 Study of the Great-Russo-Japanese Campaign in Manchuria
  - Newspaper photos of Japanese and Russians 1904, (7)
  - The Bulletin: San Francisco September 18, 1902map of the All-Rail Route across Europe and Asia
- Le Journal d'Egypte, Cairo, December 15, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 2 Part II)
- Le Journal d'Egypte, Cairo, February 8, 1939
- Le Journal d'Egypte, Cairo, February 8, 1939
- Le Journal d'Egypte, Cairo, February 11, 1939
- Le Journal d'Egypte, Cairo, February 11, 1939
- Unidentified paper Filipino Fighter Victim of Ring Battle
- The Christian Science Monitor June 9, 1943
- The Buddhist World Colombo December 3, 1952article by E-W
- The Buddhist World Colombo September 2, 1953article by E-W
- The Buddhist World Colombo December 14, 1953article by E-W
- The San Diego Union March 8, 1953
- The San Diego Union March 22, 1953
- The Christian Science Monitor July 6, 1959
- Photographs (Photographs of Indian (East) Schactar & priests, (9) (Box 8, Folder 3 Part II)
- Gold watch belonging to E-W (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Photo: Annie Besant (8/4/18)by Wiele & Klein, Madras. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- The Adyar Album, views of the headquarters of the Theosophical Society. Adyar, Madras., (26 pp)
- Six colored [Burmese?] postcards.
- Mitry's Photo studio envelope containing:
  4 [Arab?] group photos, one person of whom is probably Wentz.
  1 shoulder & head view of Wentz, printed as postcard.
- Kodak film wallet containing:
  11 black & white photos of [Northern India?]
- Postcard photo of Mt. Chocorua (N.H.)
- Light green envelope containing 8 miscellaneous Egyptian postcards.
- Wrapped in tissue:
  2 photos, taken by Charlie, June 1918.
  1 photo of Vivian and Cedric at Lloyds neck...
- 1 Postcard of Ceylon
- In large envelope, 4 mounted photos of Ceylonese (?) deities, identified on backs.
- Miscellaneous, including letters, notes and printed material. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Scale of life composition, printed.
  - 1919, Feb 18,Sudhakar to E-W, postcard.
  - 1919, Feb 21,Shradohanandu Sangosi [?] to Sir, ALs.
  - 1917, Dec 18,Times of Ceylon newsclipping re E-W in Ceylon as archaeologist.
  - n.d.,but similar to above.
  - 1919, Feb 18,Shrandhananda Sangosi [?] to Sir, ALS, with cover.
  - n.d., Sep 17,Freyda Dorntof [?] to Friend, ALS, with cover., 2 pp
  - Small note book, starts with Hymn to Ra, 18 pp.
  - 4 printed cards for Sat Yudi Mandli: or Society of hastening the coming of God's kingdom.
  - 1918,6.8., Lal Chand, letter copied re Gopal Krishna Sfo L. Hakam Chand Patni.
  - 1919,14.2. Gopal Krishna, Lahore, letter copied, 2 pp.
  - 1919, Feb 2,envelope.
  - 1919,18.2, Hari Lhusau Mukherjee to Wentz, ALS., 2 pp
  - 1919,8.2, [G.C.?] Mukherjee to Wentz, 2 pp ALS with (same sheet) continuation, (2 pp)
  - 1919, Feb 2,envelope.
  - Small green notebook with Wentz' notes on Shakti & Shakta